### ALIX MARTÍNEZ MARTÍNEZ

### INFO@ALIXMZMZ.EU 075 987 10150

beautifultosee.alixmzmz.eu

I am a designer with a visual background and experience in interaction design, currently working at Fjord London – a global service design consultancy.

Curious by nature, I create experiences focused on improving people's lives together with my teammates. I am interested in both innovation and beautiful things. Over the last 14 years I have had the chance to develop an understanding of design and our connected world, exploring its languages, cultures and methodologies.

What I value and strive to communicate: enthusiasm, positivity, proactivity and a collaborative attitude. I understand design as a balance of business goals and desired customer behaviours. I am also an art lover, light enthusiast, traveller, kickboxer...

#### **EDUCATION**

#### UNIVERSIDAD DE A CORUÑA. CAP: PEDAGOGICAL ADAPTATION COURSE.

2006 - 2007

Visual arts, fine arts, education and psychology. Professional Qualification for Teaching Specialisation.

#### SPD SCUOLA POLITECNICA DI DESIGN. MILAN, ITALY

2003 - 2004

Master's degree: Web and digital Web design, visual design, digital art direction, web technologies, html/css, flash animation, 3Ddesign.

#### GEORG-OHM-SIMON FACHHOCHSCHULE. NUREMBERG. GERMAY

2000 - 2001

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) / Erasmus, Typography, Illustration and Photography.

#### UNIVERSIDAD DE SALAMANCA. BACHELOR OF FINE ARTS. SPAIN

1996 - 2001

Graphic Design and Audiovisual Communication. Graphic design, audiovisual communication, photography, illustration, typography. Internship at the Centre "Reina Sofia" (Provincial Government of Salamanca). Visual arts designed for children with mental disabilities.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

### VISUAL DESIGN LEAD FJORD

JUL 2015 - PRESENT. LONDON, UNITED KINGDOM

Directly responsible for the Quality, Creativity and Delivery of the projects I am overseeing, along with revenue generated on these projects, and client and team satisfaction.

Responsibility for successful delivery for a range of projects. Design projects: graphic design, branding and identity strategy, illustration, photography, diagrammatic expertise (information visualisation), user experience, art direction. Internal development projects. Proposal, pitching and sales related project activities

## SENIOR VISUAL DESIGNER FJORD

MAY 2013 - JULY 2015. LONDON, UNITED KINGDOM

Responsible for the concept, creation, direction and delivery of visual design, taking into consideration the interaction design aspect.

#### ALIX MARTÍNEZ MARTÍNEZ

#### INFO@ALIXMZMZ.EU

#### 075 987 10150

beautifultosee.alixmzmz.eu

#### INTERACTIVE DESIGNER BWIN.PARTY DIGITAL ENT.

OCTOBER 2012 – MAY 2013 LONDON, UNITED KINGDOM Part of the Marketing Communications Department, working closely with account managers and art directors.

- Deliver high-quality creative solutions for all brand elements in the business to agreed standards and timeframes
- Execute briefs, from conceptual design and publishing to going live through the CMS, using front-end coding
- Identify areas to help optimise in all aspects of online marketing material

## SENIOR VISUAL DESIGNER RIPLIFE GAMING TECHNOLOGIES

SEPTEMBER 2011 – JUNE 2012 BARCELONA, SPAIN Riplife is a fast-paced Agile-focused company that provides services to major brands around the globe. As part of the UX Team, I produced websites from concept to execution and also provided support to development teams. I was always keen to lend a helping hand to produce richer and more productive user experiences within a creative team based in three different locations.

#### VISUAL DESIGNER AEDGENCY

AUGUST 2009 – JULY 2011 BARCELONA, SPAIN Aedgency operates across five European markets and millions of online shoppers have opted in to Aedgency's consumer-facing shopping tools to find the best deals. Online performance-based marketing and advertising. Concept design and delivery: sites, microsites, banners, landing pages, email, icons, installers, etc.

## LEAD VISUAL DESIGNER DEENERO. AEDGENCY

FEBRUARY 2009 – AUGUST 2009 BARCELONA, SPAIN

- · Responsible for visual design of Deenero product
- · Communication with other departments and key stakeholders
- · Training of junior designers

#### INTERACTIVE PRODUCER. GRAVITATE

SEPTEMBER 2007 – JUNE 2008 DUBLIN, IRELAND Web design (from concept to implementation), quality control, management tasks, participation in internal projects, customer support, etc.

#### VISUAL DESIGNER. AGRAFOJO+ASOCS

OCTOBER 2005 – JULY 2007 A CORUÑA, SPAIN Design and coordination. Branding, corporate identity, brochures, books and other publications, conference materials, websites, signage, shipping management for print.

#### VISUAL DESIGNER. DIMPRES!ON

MAY 2005 - OCTOBER 2005 A CORUÑA, SPAIN Offline design: branding, corporate identity, signage, design of labels, vinyl, backlights, displays, and several publications (directories, brochures, etc.).

#### VISUAL DESIGNER. UNDERGRAPHIC

FEGRUARY 2005 - MAY 2005 CAGLIARI, ITALY Advertising (newspapers, direct marketing, outdoor / indoor), corporate identity, branding, brochures, etc.

#### TEAM LEAD (ILLUSTRATION DEPT) RODEIRA-EDEBÉ

SEPTEMBER 2001 – SEPTEMBER 2003 A CORUÑA, SPAIN

- · Textbooks: image sourcing, photo retouch, illsutration
- · Quality control and proofreading
- · Candidate selection

### CURRICULUM PROJECTS DESIGNER RODEIRA-EDEBÉ

1999 - 2001. A CORUÑA, SPAIN

Curriculum design for technical drawing manuals for Spanish county councils.